**Hemant Desai** 

Email: ahemant1912@gmail.com

Phone: 9316530452

#### **Summary:**

6+ years of experience in different field Like Restaurant Supervisor Management, site supervisor, Reliance Retail Marketing, Bench sales recruiter, Extensive 15+ Month of experience in the field of IT (US - Staffing), Expert in Bench Sales including of H1B s, TN s, GC s, USC s & EAD s, coordinating with the consultant in order to know their comfortableness with the requirement before submitting to the Vendor., Posting the resume on all job portals like Dice, Monster, and social networking portals etc. Submitting the consultants to all the suitable job postings on all portals., Also known as construction site supervisors, site supervisors monitor the progress of construction projects and ensure compliance with construction safety regulations. They supervise construction workers and subcontractors, educate construction workers on site safety practices, and evaluate employee performance...Retail Marketing on medicale product and grocery product's in Reliance Marketing Industries.

#### **Education:**

Bachelor's from University of HNGU at K.S.B.L.College, Kheralu.

#### **Skills:**

Recruiting, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Word, Site Supervision, Market Information, Team Leadership, Teamwork, Management, Communication, Group Discussions

#### **Experience:**

#### **Bench Sales Recruiter (Freelance)**

September – Present

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Responsible for handling IT requirements from US based clients.
- Responsible for full-cycle recruiting: interview, offer, negotiation and closed candidates for assigned requisitions.
- Sourcing from Job Portals (LinkedIn, Indeed, Monster, Dice, Career builder, Job diva), Making job postings on the Job Portal.
- Responsible to work on Contract-Hire, Permanent and some time on a contract position.
- Responsible for achieving a good conversion ratio of submittals into interview and placement.
- Responsible for Strategy Development process which includes understanding client requirements & mapping the relevant targets.
- Posting/submitting their resumes on various job boards/requirements and finding requirements for them through other resources.
- Checking for the right requirements that match our consultant profiles on various job portals.
- Checking with the consultant's comfort on job requirements and suggesting any modifications required to improve their chances of short listing for the job positions applied.
- Working directly with end client requirements like Tier 1 vendors/Implements.

Digz Placement
Bench Sales Recruiter

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Involved in full cycle in recruitment and salesas my responsibilities are sourcing, identifying, screening, CV formation & Placing personal in quick turn around time in contract- contract to hire & Permanent position.
- In information technology industry throughout the United States (USA).
- Expert in bench sales including H1bs, TN, GC, USC & EADs.
- Attending the vendor and clint calls for the requirement.
- Posting resume on behalf of consultant info various job portals like Dice, Monsater, Indeed, Linked, etc..
- Regular Follow-ups with vendors on the feedbacks of interbiews.
- Negotiating rates and getting the best possible rates for consultant.
- Organize the feedback session on interviewed candidates.
- Keep track all candidates, submission and interviews in a database.

#### Dash Technologies INC. Bench Sales Recruiter

June 2021 – Feb 2022

#### Responsibilities:

- Get the updated resume from consultant and fetched the best requirements from job portals, prime vendors and other networking sites.
- Highlighted keys skills by keeping them in bold.
- Formatted resume for neat appearance and submitted it to the vendors as per consultant's comfort ability.
- Negotiated on rates with the vendors as suggested by management based upon location and duration.
- Keeping a track record of rate confirmation and making follow ups about the submissions. Maintained a track progress of each and every submittal during the process. Follow up with the vendors on interviews schedules and coordinated between consultants and vendors.
- Arranged interviews calls for consultants and gave my best to plkace them on project as early as possible.
- Follow up with the clint/prefer vendors and candidate after interviews.
- Responsibly coordinated with the consultants regarding start and end dates of projects.
- Maintained the database of rolled off consultants, getting their resumes ready as well as keep track of contract details such as project extensions, start and end dates for existing resources.
- Keep track of candidates roll off time (at least 2 weeks before) and getting their updated resume ready to market.
- Finding best projects to consultants using my tier one contacts and through different web portals like Dice, crop crop, Monster, Career Builder, Net-temps, Jobserve, computer jobs and professional networking sites such as LinkedIn.
- Worked with prime vendors to avoid middle layers.
- Maintained good relationship with prime vendors to get future requirements.

## Reliance Retail Gujarat, IN Retail Sales Specialist (CSO)

**April 2021 – Aug 2021** 

#### Responsibilites:

- Reliance Retail has adopted a multi-prong strategy and operates neighborhood stores, supermarkets, hypermarkets, wholesale cash & carry stores, specialty stores and online stores and has democratized access to all types of products and services across all segments for all Indian consumers.
- Shortout Customer issues.

### LLP Protocol Gujarat, IN Site Supervisor

April 2018 - Dec 2020

### Responsibilites:

• Also known as construction site supervisors, site supervisors monitor the progress of construction projects and ensure compliance with construction safety regulations.

• They supervise construction workers and subcontractors, educate construction workers on site safety practices, and evaluate employee performance

# Shukan Restaurant, IN Restaurant Supervisor Management

Jan 2016 - Feb 2018

#### Responsibilites:

- Supervising a team of staff.
- Ensuring staff are managed efficiently and meet targets.
- Servicing hospitality meeting rooms within agreed time scales.
- Ensuring areas of work are kept are kept clean throughout the day.
- Completing all meeting rooms set-ups and clearing requests on schedule.
- Managing workflow.
- Training new hires.
- Creating and managing team schedules.
- Reporting to HR and senior management.
- Evaluating performance and providing feedback.
- Identifying and applying career advancement opportunities.
- Healping to resolve employee issues and disputes.
- Done to fantastic job duration on my time period.
- Always been on time and ready to complete any task given from my manager.